<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Donato Maragno</title>
    <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Donato Maragno</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://donato-maragno.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Part 1 - Theory] Inventory Management: The Art of Balancing Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;![[inventory.jpg]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inventory management is at the heart of operations, yet it’s one of the most challenging aspects for organizations of all sizes. In this post, we explore what inventory management is, why it matters, and the key principles that guide effective decisions. I’ll introduce the most common policies, like (s, Q), (s, S), and periodic review, and explain how organizations balance costs, service levels, and risk. This foundational knowledge sets the stage for understanding how mathematics can help optimize inventory decisions in real-world settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Part 2 - Model] Inventory Management: The Art of Balancing Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-1/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we covered the fundamentals of inventory management, key policies, and how organizations think about costs and service levels. Now, we dive into the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical side&lt;/strong&gt;: how to formulate a multi-item, multi-period inventory problem as a &lt;strong&gt;mixed-integer optimization model&lt;/strong&gt;. This post will walk through the sets, parameters, decision variables, objective function, and constraints that define an optimal &lt;em&gt;(s, S)&lt;/em&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-optimal-policy-is-all-you-need&#34;&gt;An &lt;em&gt;OPTIMAL&lt;/em&gt; policy is all you need&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, you don’t just need &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; policy; you need the &lt;em&gt;optimal&lt;/em&gt; one. A policy is a rulebook for how inventory decisions are made: when to order, and how much. But among the many possible rules, some are clearly better than others in terms of cost and service. An &lt;em&gt;optimal&lt;/em&gt; policy is the one that achieves the desired objectives (high availability, low cost) without wasting resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Part 3 - Code] Inventory Management: The Art of Balancing Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-2/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we built a complete mathematical model to determine the optimal &lt;em&gt;(s, S)&lt;/em&gt; policy for multiple items over a planning horizon. Now it’s time to put theory into practice. In this post, we generate realistic synthetic data, formulate the model in &lt;strong&gt;Python using PulP&lt;/strong&gt;, solve it with an open-source solver, and visualize the results. By the end, you’ll see how the optimal reorder points and order-up-to levels unfold week by week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display:flex; align-items:flex-start; gap:2rem;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://donato-maragno.github.io/images/aboutme.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Donato Maragno&#34; style=&#34;width:2500px; height:auto; border-radius:8px;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;h2&gt;Donato Maragno&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I enjoy working at the intersection of &lt;strong&gt;AI and mathematical optimization&lt;/strong&gt; to turn complex data into &lt;strong&gt;scalable decision-making systems&lt;/strong&gt; that drive real business value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2025, I earned a PhD in Applied Mathematics and Machine Learning at the &lt;strong&gt;University of Amsterdam&lt;/strong&gt;, with a thesis on Optimization with Constraint Learning (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dare.uva.nl/search?identifier=25bcb39d-9954-4849-9479-812411bd4d36&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I worked at &lt;strong&gt;MIT&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Harvard&lt;/strong&gt; on projects ranging from democratizing optimization to personalized radiotherapy planning.&#xA;Currently, I work as a &lt;strong&gt;Scientist at Amazon&lt;/strong&gt; on projects spanning &lt;strong&gt;supply chain management, logistics, production planning, and sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;. I build optimization frameworks that are robust under uncertainty, practical and scalable for small, medium, and large industries, and able of delivering measurable impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research focuses on the intersection of &lt;strong&gt;artificial intelligence, machine learning, and mathematical optimization&lt;/strong&gt;. I explore how these tools can be combined to support better decision-making in practice, from production planning to last-mile routing and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below is a selection of the most recent publications. A complete list is available on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=2fEV-iIAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Google Scholar profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read my PhD Thesis &lt;a href=&#34;https://dare.uva.nl/search?identifier=25bcb39d-9954-4849-9479-812411bd4d36&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#39;align-center&#39;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img&#xD;&#xA;    src=&#39;https://donato-maragno.github.io/images/thesis.png&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    alt=&#39;PhD Thesis&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    width=&#39;400&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    height=&#39;600&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    style=&#39;object-fit: contain; border-radius: 8px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#39;&#xD;&#xA;  /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Decision Making Through the Integration of Large Language Models and Operations Research Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Segev Wasserkrug, Leonard Boussioux, Dick den Hertog, Farzaneh Mirzazadeh, Ş. Ilker Birbil, Jannis Kurtz, Donato Maragno&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
