<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Donato Maragno</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Donato Maragno</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inventory Management: The Art of Balancing Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>/posts/inventory-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/inventory-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/inventory.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;inventory.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I explain &lt;strong&gt;what inventory management is&lt;/strong&gt;, why it matters, and how organizations can systematically improve it using mathematical optimization. First, I discuss inventory management from a generic perspective, highlighting the key principles, policies, and challenges. Then, I dive into a practical case study on spare parts inventory management, showing how optimization can be applied to determine ideal reorder points, order quantities, and service levels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-inventory-management-and-why-does-it-matter&#34;&gt;What is inventory management, and why does it matter?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its core, inventory management is the art, and often the headache, of ensuring that the right product is available in the right place, at the right time, and at the right cost. Sounds simple, but in practice it’s one of the most complex problems in operations, especially when the number of products is large, the supply chain has multiple levels, and the costs structure has several components.&#xA;On the one hand, organizations want to keep inventories lean: holding too much stock ties up capital, increases storage costs, and risks obsolescence. On the other hand, running too lean can mean lost sales, production delays, and unsatisfied customers. The sweet spot lies somewhere in between, and finding it consistently is the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display:flex; align-items:flex-start; gap:2rem;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;/images/aboutme.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Donato Maragno&#34; style=&#34;width:2500px; height:auto; border-radius:8px;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;h2&gt;Donato Maragno&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I enjoy working at the intersection of &lt;strong&gt;AI and mathematical optimization&lt;/strong&gt; to turn complex data into &lt;strong&gt;scalable decision-making systems&lt;/strong&gt; that drive real business value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2025, I earned a PhD in Applied Mathematics and Machine Learning at the &lt;strong&gt;University of Amsterdam&lt;/strong&gt;, with a thesis on Optimization with Constraint Learning (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dare.uva.nl/search?identifier=25bcb39d-9954-4849-9479-812411bd4d36&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I worked at &lt;strong&gt;MIT&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Harvard&lt;/strong&gt; on projects ranging from democratizing optimization to personalized radiotherapy planning.&#xA;Currently, I work as a &lt;strong&gt;Scientist at Amazon&lt;/strong&gt; on projects spanning &lt;strong&gt;supply chain management, logistics, production planning, and sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;. I build optimization frameworks that are robust under uncertainty, practical and scalable for small, medium, and large industries, and able of delivering measurable impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research focuses on the intersection of &lt;strong&gt;artificial intelligence, machine learning, and mathematical optimization&lt;/strong&gt;. I explore how these tools can be combined to support better decision-making in practice, from production planning to last-mile routing and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below is a selection of the most recent publications. A complete list is available on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=2fEV-iIAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Google Scholar profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read my PhD Thesis &lt;a href=&#34;https://dare.uva.nl/search?identifier=25bcb39d-9954-4849-9479-812411bd4d36&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#39;align-center&#39;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img&#xD;&#xA;    src=&#39;/images/thesis.png&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    alt=&#39;PhD Thesis&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    width=&#39;400&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    height=&#39;600&#39;&#xD;&#xA;    style=&#39;object-fit: contain; border-radius: 8px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#39;&#xD;&#xA;  /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Decision Making Through the Integration of Large Language Models and Operations Research Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Segev Wasserkrug, Leonard Boussioux, Dick den Hertog, Farzaneh Mirzazadeh, Ş. Ilker Birbil, Jannis Kurtz, Donato Maragno&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
