<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math on Donato Maragno</title>
    <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math on Donato Maragno</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://donato-maragno.github.io/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Part 2 - Model] Inventory Management: The Art of Balancing Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-1/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we covered the fundamentals of inventory management, key policies, and how organizations think about costs and service levels. Now, we dive into the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical side&lt;/strong&gt;: how to formulate a multi-item, multi-period inventory problem as a &lt;strong&gt;mixed-integer optimization model&lt;/strong&gt;. This post will walk through the sets, parameters, decision variables, objective function, and constraints that define an optimal &lt;em&gt;(s, S)&lt;/em&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-optimal-policy-is-all-you-need&#34;&gt;An &lt;em&gt;OPTIMAL&lt;/em&gt; policy is all you need&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, you don’t just need &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; policy; you need the &lt;em&gt;optimal&lt;/em&gt; one. A policy is a rulebook for how inventory decisions are made: when to order, and how much. But among the many possible rules, some are clearly better than others in terms of cost and service. An &lt;em&gt;optimal&lt;/em&gt; policy is the one that achieves the desired objectives (high availability, low cost) without wasting resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Part 3 - Code] Inventory Management: The Art of Balancing Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://donato-maragno.github.io/posts/inventory-management---part-2/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we built a complete mathematical model to determine the optimal &lt;em&gt;(s, S)&lt;/em&gt; policy for multiple items over a planning horizon. Now it’s time to put theory into practice. In this post, we generate realistic synthetic data, formulate the model in &lt;strong&gt;Python using PulP&lt;/strong&gt;, solve it with an open-source solver, and visualize the results. By the end, you’ll see how the optimal reorder points and order-up-to levels unfold week by week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
